
Author's Word about CmdWiz: (Source: https://www.dostips.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=7402)
-by misol101

This program has been wedged in between my other two programs cmdgfx.exe and gotoxy.exe for some time. This thread is mostly to get some documentation up.

Now supports Unicode!

What is it?
Cmdwiz is a helper tool to do all sorts of useful things in batch scripts (and outside).

Where is it?
I don't want to maintain yet another archive so I'll point to gotoxy.zip, where cmdwiz.exe is included: http://www.mediafire.com/download/8xywd ... gotoxy.zip
(open link in new tab if it doesn't load)

What operations does cmdwiz support?
As of CmdWiz v1.4, there are currently 52 of them, and they can be divided as follows:
1. Set/get windows/cmd buffer size, position and look
2. Reading input from keyboard and/or mouse
3. Setting and saving the current console font
4. Get character and colors in the buffer/system
5. Setting the cursor position/look and writing text
6. Working with strings
7. Working with timing/delay
8. Moving and clicking with the mouse cursor and sending key events
9. Moving, saving or examining blocks of characters
10. Miscellaneous operations
All operations support "cmdwiz operation /?" to get info on arguments and return values.


There are no operations to write colored text or special characters, which might be expected in a tool such as this.

This is because all that is done by my other tool "gotoxy.exe" (see http://www.dostips.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=7129), which has many ways to accomplish that task and much more (note: gotoxy.exe is also included in the above archive).

Also, for more heavy graphics and games, there is "cmdgfx.exe", see http://www.dostips.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=7153.


Note on arguments:
I don't follow the normal convention where arguments surrounded by [] are strictly optional.

For cmdwiz (and my other tools), arguments surrounded by [] ARE optional, *but* if you want to specify the following argument(s) (in order from Left to Right), then they are NOT optional.

Example: cmdwiz operation [op1] [op2] [op3 op4]

Here, op1 is optional, as is op2, but to specify op2 you must specify op1. Next comes op3 and op4, for which op1 and op2 must both be given first. Op3/op4 must be specified together, since they are within the same block.

To write the above strictly correct, it would look like: cmdwiz operation [op1 [op2 [op3 op4]]], which I personally find confusing, so I just don't.

Think of it as default arguments in a C++ function. Hopefully the operation is constructed so that you should not want to specify op2 without specifying op1 (though not always true)